awea.org 2016-06-07

# American Wind Energy Association Privacy Policy

**I. Introduction**

This is the official Privacy Policy of the American Wind Energy Association ("AWEA," "we," "us," or "our"). 

We are committed to protecting the privacy of our members and those who visit our Site. The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to inform you about the types of information we gather about you, including information gathered when you visit AWEA’s official website located at www.awea.org, AWEA’s social media pages, AWEA’s mobile site or downloadable mobile applications (collectively, the "Site"), and information we may receive from third parties or affiliates, how we may use that information, whether we disclose that information to anyone, and the choices you have regarding our use of, and your ability to correct, the information.  By using the Site, you expressly consent to the use and disclosure of information as described in this Privacy Policy. 

We collect two types of information: personally identifiable information and non-personally identifiable information.  Personally identifiable information is information that identifies you or can be used to identify or contact you ("Personally Identifiable Information").  We also may collect information that by itself typically cannot be used to identify or contact you, such as demographic information (e.g. age, profession or gender), IP addresses, browser types, domain names, and other anonymous statistical data involving the use of our Site ("Non-Personally Identifiable Information").  The non-personally identifiable information may also include information about the company at which you are employed, if that company is a member, sponsor, or affiliate of AWEA.

This Site is governed by laws and regulations of the United States ("U.S.").  If you are not a resident of the U.S. and you chose to join the AWEA, to participate in AWEA events and activities that require the submission of your Personally Identifiable Information, or otherwise provide AWEA with Personally Identifiable Information you hereby freely consent to the transfer and processing of your Personally Identifiable Information to the U.S. and you consent to be governed by the laws and regulations of the U.S. with regards to the use of your Personally Identifiable Information.

We reserve the right to modify this Policy at any time without prior notice. When we modify the Policy, we will post the revised Policy on this Site.

**II. Collection and Use of Personally Identifiable Information**

This Privacy Policy governs all forms of Personally Identifiable Information collected by AWEA offline and online.  We collect Personally Identifiable Information online and offline only if you choose to provide it to us.  If you choose to apply for an AWEA membership, register for an AWEA conference or seminar, order a publication, participate in an AWEA event, or make a donation, we will ask you to provide information that may include your name, job title, name of company, business address, business phone, fax number and e-mail address.  AWEA does not collect home addresses, home phone numbers or home e-mail accounts unless you decide to provide this information to AWEA.  We will also collect certain information about member companies that may include office location(s), company size, and industry classification.

We collect a credit or debit card account number, along with the expiration date and security code, from members or other individuals to pay for membership dues, AWEA events fees, publications, audio or video materials and other contributions.   When members or other individuals choose to pay by check, we do not store checking account information. Payment information is retained for administrative and tax purposes.

If you are a member of AWEA we list company name and company contact information to compile an Annual Membership Directory for the personal and professional use of AWEA members.  This directory may include your individual name if your company indicates that you are the primary contact for AWEA membership.  Every effort is made to ensure the accuracy of the information contained in the Directory.  Online access to the Directory is password protected and restricted for use only by AWEA members and organizational staff.  If you serve on an AWEA Committee or Working Group, your name may be listed as a member of that entity.  For committee and working group leaders, AWEA may also include a brief biography but only with your permission. We may include your name, photo, and quotations and/or video for member testimonials, with your permission.

Information on the AWEA.org website includes industry news and case studies that may list names and other individual information as part of the document.  To the extent AWEA produces such information, AWEA takes all reasonable steps to screen out personal data other than individual or company names.   AWEA is not responsible for data that may be captured in news stories and reference materials provided by sources other than AWEA that are linked to via the AWEA.org website. 

In addition to AWEA.org, AWEA may maintain supplemental related websites such as the Power of Wind website.  Where those websites facilitate grassroots activities, AWEA may collect individual data including name, company name, address, and email address.  It may also collect specific demographic data, which the individual user may provide at their own option.

To the extent we are able to do so, we may link your Non-Personally Identifiable Information with your Personally Identifiable Information.  We may also link information collected online with information we collect offline or that is collected online by third parties.

**III.   Sharing of Personally Identifiable Information**

We may share your email address with other organizations that are co-sponsors or co-presenters of an AWEA event.  lf you are a non-member, we will also use your email address for AWEA-related promotional purposes.  We do not disclose your email address to non-related third parties for marketing purposes.  If you wish to be removed from our email distribution list, please call AWEA at (202) 383-2500 **.** We also share information with our affiliates and within AWEA to improve service to our members and to enhance our organization's effectiveness.

AWEA may provide your personal information to service providers or contractors to perform functions on its behalf, such as, but not limited to, companies or individuals hired to: communicate news, deliver AWEA's promotional materials via e-mail and direct mail, assist with organizing, operating or marketing AWEA events, promote AWEA's social media presence and activities, to develop, enhance, market or provide any of AWEA's products or services, to process credit card payments and to assist AWEA with sending communications and performing other marketing and support functions.  All third-party operational service providers used by the AWEA are required to comply with AWEA's Privacy Policy and practices. Also, AWEA may use third-party social media platforms, including third-party social media websites, to communicate with you. 

We also may share with third parties aggregated demographic and statistical information that is not personally identifiable.

To the extent permitted by law, we may disclose your Personally Identifiable Information to government authorities or third parties pursuant to a legal request, subpoena, to comply with other legal process, or upon a law enforcement agency’s (or other governmental agency’s) request.  We may also use or disclose your Personally Identifiable Information to protect the rights or property of the AWEA, and the rights, safety or security of our members, our employees, our Site, or its users, and to enforce our Terms of Use Agreement.  Finally, we may disclose your Personally Identifiable Information to any other entity that acquires all or a portion of our organization by merger, reorganization, operation of law, or a sale of some or all of AWEA's assets.

**IV. The Children's Online Privacy Protection Act**

The AWEA does not knowingly collect Personally Identifiable Information from children under the age of 13 without prior verifiable parental consent.  If AWEA learns that, despite these measures, a child under the age of 13 has submitted Personally Identifiable Information to AWEA through the Site, it will take reasonable measures to delete such information from its records and to not use such information for any purpose (except where necessary to protect the safety of the child or others as required by law).

**V. Cookies and Other Technology**

By using our Site, some Non-Personally Identifiable Information may be automatically collected by our web servers as you browse our Site.  For example, our web server automatically collects information known as "click stream data," such as the domain name of the site providing you with Internet access, the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet, your browser type and version, operating system and platform, the average time spent on our site, pages viewed, information searched for, access times and other relevant statistics. We also collect information by using technologies and methodologies that enable tracking, such as "cookies". "Cookies" are small pieces of information that a website transfers to the hard drive of a visitor's computer for record-keeping purposes. "Cookies" provide visitors a personalized experience on our site by enabling us to determine unique preferences and trends based on visits to our website and to other websites.

**VI. Protecting Your Personally Identifiable Information**

AWEA is committed to protecting the security of your Personally Identifiable Information. We use commercially reasonable security technologies and procedures to protect your Personally Identifiable Information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure.  After you have submitted your information online to AWEA, we recommend that you end your browser session before leaving your computer.  In spite of these protections, AWEA cannot guarantee the security of any data submitted over the Internet.  After your information reaches AWEA, however, it is stored on servers (or in the case of information received from you in person, in writing or over the phone, in physical storage areas) protected by procedures and technology designed to block reasonably foreseeable intrusions by unauthorized third parties. 

**VII. Access to and Review of Your Personally Identifiable Information**

If you would like to review, modify and/ or correct your Personally Identifiable Information, please contact us at 202-383-2500 and request to be connected to the Membership department.   You must authenticate your identity before we provide access to your Personally Identifiable Information.

**VIII. External Links**

This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by AWEA.  In order to assist you and provide you as much information as possible, our Site contains links to other websites including those that offer information of professional interest to our membership.  This Privacy Policy does not apply to other websites that are accessible through this Site, including but not limited to any third-party websites that process payments on behalf of AWEA.  AWEA is not responsible for the business or privacy practices or the content of such external websites.  Therefore, we encourage you to review the privacy policy and terms and conditions of any third-party website linked to this Site before you submit any Personally Identifiable Information.

**IX. Contact Us**

 If you have any questions or comments, please contact us at: 202-383-2500.
